JEFF JOHNSON

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

CONTACT

703.585.7018

in linkedin.com/in/iiohnso8

Syracuse, NY

mightymosjeff.com

SKILLS

// LANGUAGES

JavaScript

TypeScript

JAVA

HTML

CSS

// FRAMEWORKS & TOOLS

Front-end: React, Next.js

Back-end: Node.js, Express, Fastify

State Management: Redux, Zustand

APIs: GraphQL, REST

Databases: PostgreSQL, mongoDB, MvSQL

MySQL

UX: Chakra UI, Tailwind, Theme UI, Material UI, Bootstrap

Testing: Jest, React Testing Library,

Cypress **Repository Management:** git, Nx,

Turborepo

Other tools: Stripe, Shopify, Framer Motion

EDUCATION

BACHELORS OF SCIENCE Computer Engineering

University of Notre Dame Notre Dame, IN

SUMMARY

I am a software engineer with more than 20 years of experience seeking a role with a focus on frontend development. I am looking for an individual contributor role, but I do have a great deal of experience managing and mentoring junior developers.

I like creating pretty UIs, but I also like writing beautiful code. I am a design system nerd. I will make a passionate argument for what I believe is right, but I am also very open to the ideas of others. I believe kindness and empathy are important. We all make mistakes, and I take ownership of mine. I think there should be more pairing sessions and fewer meetings. I am not immune to imposter syndrome. Standards are important, but so is flexibility. I believe that the best lessons you can learn as a developer come through the vulnerability of a code review.

EXPERIENCE

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2024 - Present

ComplyAuto

- Led development effort for an app that allows auto dealerships to automatically report injury and illness data to OSHA as required by law.
- Built a UI that enables clients to create custom safety assessment templates tailored to
 their unique business needs. The UI design is very complex, involving animations and
 interactions between nested accordion components that could also be dragged and
 reordered on the page.
- Developed a barcode scanning feature so that customers could scan a QR code on a piece
 of equipment in their warehouse and directly launch a safety equipment checklist
 required by state and/or federal guidelines.

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Jan 2023 - Jan 2024

Curiosity Media

- Helped launch a leaderboards feature to SpanishDictionary.com to increase user engagement and drive premium subscriptions. Was responsible for designing the data store and backend APIs, as well as developing some of the major UI components for displaying leaderboard data.
- Developed an SDK for the SpanishDictionary site to more easily and consistently connect with the backend server. This included features like results caching, DNS caching and standardized logging.
- Responsible for site performance with a focus on improving observability, measurement and profiling of applications.

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Mar 2020 - Jan 2023

School of Motion

- Architected and designed the next-generation of SOM's first-class Learning Management System (LMS).
- Enhanced and maintained SOM's existing LMS, including significant performance improvements.
- Created design system and UX component library to match SOM's brand guidelines and design principles.
- Managed third party integrations, including Stripe and Shopify.
- Reported directly to the CEO, providing data and analytics to help measure KPIs.

JEFF JOHNSON

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

PRINCIPAL CONSULTANT

Aug 2011 - Mar 2020

Blackboard

- Architected and developed a cloud-based front-end application stack used to develop subscription services for many customers.
- Led development of a Java microservices platform used across several Blackboard products.
- Architected and developed a desktop application that allowed students to interact with their courses offline.
- Developed a cloud-based integration with many large textbook publishers and technology companies around the world.
- Worked jointly with Bb's Product Development team to add features to the core Bb Learn product so that they could get to market more quickly.

TECHNICAL LEAD

Aug 2009 - Aug 2011

2020, LLC

- Led a team of 5 developers in designing, developing and maintaining the US Department of Education's largest data collection.
- Owned the project plan and release schedule, facilitated client meetings and communicated project status to stakeholders.
- Secured a large deal with the US Patent and Trade Office by providing a written proposal and oral arguments to the customer.

MANAGER, CONSULTING SERVICES

May 2006 - Aug 2009

Blackboard

- Managed a team of 10 people in day to day operations, including career development, escalation support, staffing and technical mentoring.
- Supported business development in the K-12 and North American Higher Ed markets.
- Managed the technical elements of several projects for a large K-12 Education client.
- Selected to speak at the 2007 and 2008 Blackboard Developers Conferences.

CONSULTANT

Oct 2002 - May 2006

Accenture

- Led data conversion development effort for the State of Michigan's child support system, a large-scale Oracle implementation.
- Developed J2EE portal applications and implemented custom content management systems for the National Geospatial-Intelligence Agency (NGA).